柏林市区  1750km
莫斯科  35km
把斧头给我
Give me the Axe.
快点砍
Chop faster.
这有点恐怖
It's scary here.
中尉
Lieutenant...
这样就舒服了
There, that's better.
有德国人
Germans
我们走
Let's move out
你要去哪  你疯了吗
Where are you going? Are you crazy?
从它右侧绕过去
We'll swing right by them.
它得扭转炮塔才能开火
They'd have to turn the turret to fire on us.
等到他们炮塔锁定我们了  就数四声
Once they have locked the turret on us then count to 4
一
二  三  四
好戏开始了  接着数  就现在
Here we go. Count again, now.
快数
Count.
二  三  四
打到汽油了  我们死定了  快点离开
We're gonna' die. Hit the gas. Let's get out of here.
快数
Count.
二  三  四
他改变了开炮策略
He has changed the loading pattern.
抓稳了
Hold on.
我们活下来了  怎么样
We're alive. Yeah, somehow?
科尔贾
Kolja
瓦西洛夫
Vasilov
雷泽达  我是托波尔  这有10辆四号坦克
Rezeda, it's Topol here. 10-4
你得阻止他们
You have to stop them.
我明白  我明白
I understand. I understand.
请重复 请重复
Repeat. Repeat.
营地呢
battalion.
上校同志  营地只剩一辆坦克了
Comrade Colonel, the Battalion has only a single tank left.
其他的都哪去了
What else is there?
这里一切都被击毁了 包括半数的步兵
Here. Everything is shot up, as well as half of the infantry.
而且坦克部队没有指挥官
And the tank unit has no commander,
坦克兵几乎都严重烧伤
our men were all badly burned.
-包括我在内  -我们要战斗至最后一刻
-Yes, myself included... -We fought to the death.
我明白我们必须战斗到最后一刻
I understand we must to fight to the death.
有火吗
Give me a light.
德国人正朝着涅菲尔多进发
The Germans are heading towards Nyefjodov.
我来进行指挥
I will command.
我们必须守住这个村子
This village must be manned by troops
掩护从战地医院撤退的部队
to cover the retreat of the brigade and from the hospital.
早上好  上尉同志
Good morning, Comrade Captain.
中尉伊夫斯金向您报道  并听从您的指挥
Lieutenant Ivuskin here and waiting for your orders.
在来的路上
My report on the way here
补给卡车遭遇了敌军坦克袭击
an enemy tank attacked our supply truck
但是部队的熟食安全送达
but the troops' hot food is delivered.
-你是装甲部队的吗  -是的
-Are you an armour tank soldier? -Yes
兄弟
my brother
本来以为斯大林要来  但是我们等到了你
We expected Stalin... but we got you.
坦克班  列队
Tank squad, line up.
注意
Pay attention
我要给你们介绍新的指挥官
I'll introduce your new commander.
伊夫斯金中尉  请热烈欢迎
Lieutenant Ivuskin. Please accept him with love.
早上好  同志们
Good morning comrades.
早上好
Good morning...
伊夫斯金同志为战斗而来
Ivuskin has arrived for combat duty.
他现在是我们最后的希望
He now carries all our hopes
祝你们好运
Good luck.
去你妈的
Go to hell.
稍息
At ease.
为什么你们气氛这么紧张
Why do I see that your mood is sour?
别管闲事  临时指挥官
Outline the task Commander
德国人要攻破涅菲尔多
The Germans broke through to the village of Nyefjodov.
我们的任务就是守住这个村子
Our task is to keep the village.
让我们评估下战斗力
Let's assess the remaining troop strength
还有确定一下撤退计划
and the brigade plus the hospital retreat plans.
所以对面有多少德国人  同志
So how many Germans are there, Comrade?
根据情报至少有一百人
According to intelligence, more than a hundred.
-我们呢  -只有一辆坦克
-Our Infantry? -Only a tank.
你在逗我吗
Oh what fun this will be or what?
就一辆没有后援的坦克吗
A tank without infantry support?
还有几个步兵也和我们一起
Support. We'll scrape together a few infantry men.
我们就像傻逼一样
We... we are fools.
帕夫洛把你手枪给我  我干脆自杀算了
Pavlo, give me your revolver, I'll shoot myself now.
闭嘴
Shut up.
中尉同志我们已经一周没睡了
Lieutenant, we have been fighting for a week we have had no sleep,
我们还能站着已经是个奇迹了
it is a wonder we are still standing up.
我们是这个营仅剩的了
We're all that is left of a battalion.
接下来要我们去哪  屠宰场吗
What is next for us? The slaughterhouse?
指挥官  这里就是前线
Commander, this is the front.
你这辈子到过前线吗
Have you ever even been to the front?
在前线上你能告诉我们什么
What can you tell us about the front?
好的  你们已经表达过你们的担忧了
OK, you you have aired your concerns.
现在听我说
Now listen to me.
或许我还没真正到过前线  但是我可以告诉你们
Maybe I haven't actually seen a front yet, but I can tell you all
在指挥官培训中
that in Commander Training
我受到了最高级别的嘉奖
I received the highest graduating honors.
来这边
Now this way.
你们这群傻子怎么
Why not simply arrange an early vacation
不在进坦克前放个假
by leaving a dummy in the tank?
然后颤栗着躲在避难所里
and go on to cowardly live in an ayslum?
你们认为火炮
What is the range of your cannon?
射击范围只有1.5千米
You think it is one and a half kilometers.
我们必须至少打2公里远
We must get at least two kilometers.
埃卢斯塔尔克同志
Comrade Ellustultak?
你们用的什么类型的弹药
What kind of ammunition are you using?
你甚至不知道这种最基本的事情
You don't even know this basic fact.
-同志你姓什么  -瓦西里翁
-Comrade, your family name? -Vasilions.
引擎是热的  瓦西里翁  这点你做的很好
The engine was warmed up, Vasilions, that's good.
但是为什么排气管漏油
And why is oil leaking into the smokey exhaust?
-把漏油修好  -明白
-Stop the leak. -I understand.
我们有一个任务
We now have a mission.
而且我警告你们  在这个团队里
and I warn you, any whining in this crew
任何抱怨都会被视作怯战
I will consider it as cowardice.
我可以根据军事法依法惩处
And I will punish you according to the laws of war.
你们听明白了吗
It that understood?
在莫斯科敌军已近兵临城下了
The enemy at the walls of Moscow.
你们不能抱怨而且别再扭扭捏捏了
You don't whine here, and don't be ashamed.
只要我们凝聚起来  每个乘员各司其职
Even a single tank is a great force,
即便只有一辆坦克也是一股强大的力量
if the crew is cohesive and each tank member knows his job.
中尉  你与古布利贾见面的时间到了
Lieutenant, Your meeting with Gobulija's is approaching.
下士同志  请给我一分钟
Corporal, OK one more minute, please.
坦克班全体注意
Tank squad attention.
立正
Heads up.
听我命令
Obey my every command.
把坦克再检查一遍  做好战斗准备
Double check the tank unit, and prepare for battle.
装载上标准1.5倍的弹药
Load 150% of the standard ammunition allocation.
抛弃一切多余负重
Remove all excess weight.
指挥官同志  我能带上我的手风琴吗
Comrade Commander, can my accordion stay?
-你弹得好吗  -通常来说挺好的
-Do you play well? -Normally I do.
那我允许带手风琴
I will allow one accordion.
危机号
Crisis
在拂晓时分  我们将暴露在德国鬼子的视线里
At dawn in the morning We are within eyesight of the Gerrys.
你的坦克班要部署在这里
Your tank squad will be here.
然后我们在这接应他们撤退
And over here I will be picking them off.
德国鬼子过来的路  路境非常糟糕
The road turns, coming from the Gerry's side.
你是个优秀的战术家  古布利贾同志
You're a great strategist, Comrade Gobulija.
只是经验丰富罢了
It's just experience.
需要我帮忙吗
Can I help you?
我们能解决好  指挥官同志
We'll deal with it, Comrade Commander.
你毕竟是指挥官
OK, you are the commander.
亲爱的母亲  请不要担心  我很好
Dear mother, don't worry. I'm fine.
我们要去打德国鬼子  把他们赶走
We will break through the Gerrys to get out.
替我向曼耶阿姨问好
Say Hi to Aunt Manye.
爱你的柯拉
Kiss, Kola.
俄国人总是能绝地反击
The Russians can make always something out of nothing.
你是这样想的吗
You think?
这个村子看起来很祥和
The village seems peaceful.
别忘这点  沃夫
Don't forget Wolf,
俄国佬总是在谋划着什么
Russians are always preparing for something.
喝咖啡吗
Coffee?
这地方的雪是不详之雪
Cursed frost.
你不可能习惯这个鬼地方的
It is impossible to get used to.
我的胡子能保温
The beard can warm the face.
你怎么不留胡子 你看起来像是伊万
When do you shave? You look an Ivan.
伊万是一位有着浓密胡须的俄国沙皇
从现在开始我持续刮胡子一个星期  一个星期后我们就占领莫斯科了
I'll shave one week from now, when we occupy Moscow.
到那时我将是第一个踏上红场的德国人
By  this clock I say we will be the first Germans into Red Square.
首先我们要能到那里
First we have to get there.
启动引擎
Start the engines.
坦克准备  前方二十五米
Tanks to prepare. Distance is 25 meters.
前进
Forward. Move out.
他们排成直线  像煤油桶一样
They are lined up, like kerosene barrels.
三  四  五
他们开的很慢
They are coming nicely.
像母鸡后面领着一群鸡仔
Like chicks behind a mother hen.
那辆坦克我看起来似曾相识
This hen looks familiar to me.
我们要开炮吗
Well, ,do we knock once?
乘组人员  战斗准备
Crew, fight.
收到  指挥官
I understand, Commander.
科布扎连科  装载反坦克弹药
Kobzarenko, load anti-tank round.
装载完毕
Ready.
指挥官 战斗马上打响了
Now, Commander, soon it starts.
他停下来了  没继续数数了
He's stopped, not continuing further.
别担心  同志
Don't worry, Comrade.
好的  朝这边来啊
Well, turn to the side.
来啊  来啊
Come on, come on.
各坦克  停止前进
Tanks, stop.
关闭引擎
Stop the engines.
他似乎察觉到了什么
He senses something unusual.
-发生了什么 -安静都安静点
-What, what happened? -Silence, silence for everyone.
这里太安静了  连一声狗叫都没有
It's way too quiet. Even the dogs are not barking.
德国鬼子  过来啊  我们都盼着你过来呢
Come on, Guram, all our hopes are riding on you.
全体注意  朝十一点方向的仓库开火
Attention. Fire on the barn at the 11 o'clock position.
这就对了 德国鬼子们
This is it. It was good, Guran.
对方上钩了
He's taking the bait.
继续继续  去他妈的德国佬  建议你们找好掩体
Come on, come on, go away Guram, go away, and take cover.
22号 33号打掉仓库的火炮
陷阱设好了 赶紧走
The trap is set. Now get out of the way.
瓦茨茨基
Vaszticski.
你他妈个呆逼  赶紧跑啊
You dumb mother fucker. Get out.
下令开火啊  我们在等什么
Shoot Commander shoot, what are you waiting for?
时机未到  上士同志
It is a tat too early, senior comrade.
小鸭子们  嘎嘎
Well ducklings. Quack quack.
指挥车正好在那
The mother hen is just about there
一箭双雕
Two birds with one shot.
敌方坦克在14  15角度干草垛下  干掉它
Enemy tank under the haystack at 14, 15, degrees. Destroy it.
对方减员三辆坦克  太棒了
Three tanks less. This is it.
-瓦西里翁  驶离这里  -收到
-Vasilions, Get us out of here. -I understand.
瓦西里你他妈的在干什么  快带我们离开这
Vasilies, what the hell are you doing. Get us the hell out of here.
他们的机枪在朝我们开火
They are peppering us with machine gun fire
对面指挥车要朝我们开火了
their mother hen is all upset.
沃夫  你他妈的还在等什么
Wolf, what the hell are you waiting for?
我知道怎么做  该死  你别瞎几把催了
I know what I'm doing. Damn it, you don't go to the forehead.
开火
Fire.
让我们碾碎他们吧 指挥官
Let's crash them, Commander.
干他娘的
Give them.
还说我是初到前线的新兵
I'm a beginner on the front.
瓦西里翁把车挪到预定位置
Vasilions, put us in the button down reserve position.
开火
Fire. Fire.
我看不到任何有价值的目标  结束开火
I can't see any good targets. Firing finished.
-同志  让我开枪吧  -再等等  还不到时候
-Comrade, let me start shooting. -Wait, not yet.
等到再打掉一辆坦克
We're have to wait for the next tank.
又干掉一辆
Another one bites the dust.
对方少了四辆坦克
Minus four tanks.
开枪
Come on.
炮塔转向俩点钟方向  瞄准仓库
Rotate turret to two o'clock position. Target the barn.
收到  已经做好射击准备
Roger that. Get ready to shoot.
预备 开火
Ready. Fire.
该死
Dam that devil.
我们走
Let's get out.
步兵  用烟雾掩护坦克
Infantry, cover that tank with smoke.
瓦西里翁  撤退  德国鬼子就在外面
Vasilions, pull out. Gerry's are out there.
我猜也是这样
I guessed it.
我去找马凯耶夫  守住这里
That's Makeyev. Hold the position.
收到
Roger that.
-不惜一切代价  -是
-At all costs. -I understand.
迎接来自喜剧演员的热烈问候吧
Welcome greetings from the Amur comedian.
再见
Goodbye.
全速前进  在门口停下
Full speed ahead. Stop at the gate.
收到
Roger that.
第五个  打掉了第五个坦克
The fifth. The fifth tank.
前进  离开仓库
Forward. Get out of the barn.
-都还好吗  -瓦西里翁  向右转
-Crew. -Vasilions, sharp right.
马上
Immediately.
向右转
Sharp right.
它动不了了
It won't turn.
快啊
Come on.
离开仓库
Get out of the barn.
德国人在右边
Germans from the right.
我们走  压到最低档
Let's go. Floor it.
我们村民被敌军包围了
Us villagers are surrounded by wolves.
今日课程  "新泽西州"
Lesson for today: "Szülőföldem Village"
坦克  停下
Tank, stop.
炮塔转向到一点钟方向
rotate turret to 1 o'clock position
科布扎连科  装载反坦克炮弹
Kobzarenko load anti-tank shell.
就是现在
Right now.
俄方坦克已毁
Russian tank destroyed.
我们还活着吗
Are we alive?
万尼亚
Vanya.
不  万尼亚
No Vanya.
各位安静
Silence everyone.
同志
Comrade.
-同志  -手榴弹
-Comrade ... -the grenade ...
科布扎连科  装载反坦克炮弹
Kobzarenko load anti-tank shell.
瓦西里翁  转弯  带我们离开这里
Vasilions, bend, take us out of here.
-收到  -快点  小子
-I understand. -Come on, baby.
这是什么
What is this?
注意
Attention
动啊
Move, come on.
好了
Ready.
随意开火
Fire without a command.
聪明
Clever.
把德军挡在棚口
Stop the Germans at the stall gate.
为了你
For you.
该死  小心右边
Come on right.
停下
Stop.
后退  后退  离开这里
Back. Back. Get out of here, baby.
妈的
Damn.
冷静一下  冷静一下  沃夫
Clam down. Calm down, Wolf.
-同志  -怎么了
-Comrade. -Yes.
你叫什么名字
What's your first name?
斯蒂潘 莱瓦內维奇
I am Stepan Levanevich.
那一招很聪明  斯蒂潘 莱瓦內维奇
That was smart, Stepan Sevenevich.
谢谢你服役
Thanks for your service.
一切为了人民
I serve the working people.
好吧  现在就你和我了
All right, it's now you and me.
这样吧  德国佬  来吧  让我们聊聊
What about it Fritz? Come on, let's talk?
燃烧起来  斯蒂潘 莱瓦內维奇
Burn, Stepan Levanevich.
如果你心怀希望  那么奇迹就会发生
If you want a miracle, then it will be a miracle.
斯温
Sven.
前进
Forward.
科布扎连科  装载反坦克炮弹
Kobzarenko load anti-tank shell.
瓦西里翁  支援他
Vasilions, back up.
去樱桃园的白房子那
To the white house in the cherry garden ...
随意开火
Fire without a command.
绕开樱桃树  他迷上了那棵树
Swerved over the cherry tree he's intoxicated...
农民在耕种
Peasants are plowing,
啁啾鸟跟随着女孩们
Girls are followed by chirpping birds,
母亲们还在等待晚餐时间
And the mothers are waiting for dinner
妈的
Fuck that devil.
我受了很重的伤
I'm hurt badly.
沃夫  振作起来  你会死在这的
Wolf, pull yourself together. You want to die here.
左转90度
Turn left at 90 degrees.
停
Stop.
我站不起来了
I can not stand.
沃夫
Wolf.
准备开火  士兵
Get ready to fire, soldier.
驾驶员  从屋墙前横穿过去
Driver, cross in front of the house wall.
母亲们还在等待晚餐时间
And the mothers are waiting for dinner
开火
Fire.
妈的
Shit
斯温  瞄准他们的燃油箱
Sven. Target their fuel tank.
1944年  第三帝国
图林根集中营
Thuringia concentration camp s iii
欢迎来度假
Welcome to the resort.
这是一个特别的度假胜地
This is a special resort.
这里我们把小羊羔和山羊隔离开
Here we separate the lambs from the goats.
来这里的人  别忘了
And who is here, don't you forget ...
这里没有思想
here there are no thoughts
这里没有情感
here there are no feelings.
我们德国人是你们的主人
We Germans are your lords.
我们德国人决定你们的生死
We Germans decide whether you live or die.
立正
Attention.
趴下
Fall to the ground.
看着我  你是俄罗斯人吗
Look at me. Are you Russian?
长官  他是俄军坦克手
Commander, this is the Russian tanker.
姓名和军衔不详  他已经逃跑7次了
His name and grade are not known. He has escaped 7 times.
你叫什么名字  什么军衔
Your Name? Your rank?
问你呢  你的名字和军衔
I asked you, What is your name and rank?
请回答  你不能在这一点上沉默
Answer, please, you can't be silent on this.
今天是你的幸运日  坦克手
It's your lucky day tanker.
但你一定很想死吧
But you must have a death wish?
-带他去特别小组  -收到
-Take him to the special unit. -Yes.
说出你的名字和军衔
Name and rank?
别弄死他了  他会开口的
Listen, don't die. He'll talk.
他们到了
They're here.
各位  这是里希夫乌勒先生
Gentlemen. Mr. Reichsführer .
古德里安上将给我看了
General Guderian showed me
你的报告  贾格尔上校
your report, Jäger standartenführer .
你说的很及时
This is a timely thought.
里希夫乌勒  不久俄军坦克将会穿过我们的边界
Reichsführer, soon Russian tanks will cross our border.
要是我们不采取紧急行动  帝国就要遭罪了
If we don't take urgent action, the Reich could suffer.
我想创建一个新的坦克作战编队
I want to create a new tank fighting corps
一代足以粉碎红军的超级战士
a generation of super-fighters which can crush the Red Army.
你恨俄罗斯吗  贾格尔
You hate the Russians, Jäger?
我是一名士兵  士兵没有感情
I'm a soldier. Soldiers don't have emotions.
我的责任是服务我的国家
My duty is to serve my country.
总督察
Chief Inspector,
我任命贾格尔上校为 希特勒专属党卫队装甲班
I appoint Jäger standartenführer Hitlerjugend SS Armor Class
新坦克学员营的指挥官
commander of the new tank cadets battalion .
明白  里希夫乌勒先生
I understand, Mr Reichsführer .
德国的安危就掌握在你手里了  上校
The security of the Reich is in your hands, Standartenführer.
希特勒万岁
Heil Hitler.
一个有27个俄罗斯士兵  上校
All 27 Russian soldiers Standartenführer.
-有什么问题 吗 -没有  长官
-The problem. -No commander.
说明一下
Let me explain.
为了避免报复  有时被俘军官不会说出军衔
To avoid retaliation, sometimes captive officers do not admit rank
或是装成普通士兵以保持低调
or they surrendered to regular soldiers to keep a low profile.
好吧  但无论是谁用这种方式隐藏身份
All right. But whoever conceals himself this way
一定有一个活下去的充分理由
must have a good reason to live.
我需要一个有求生欲的俄罗斯坦克指挥官
I need a Russian tank commander who wants to live.
坦克指挥官
Tanks Commander.
这是谁
Who is this?
恐怕这不是你要的  上校
I'm afraid this is just the reverse case, Standartenführer.
他被叫做伊万  有着某些不寻常的求死欲望
He is called Ivan, he has some strange death wish.
从1941年就被监禁了
Has been in captivity since 1941,
但他一直没有透露过姓名和军衔
but still he did not disclose either his name or his rank.
此外  他逃跑过7次
Plus he escaped 7 times.
还被判处了死刑
he has been delivered for execution.
贾格尔  怎么了
Jäger  All right?
我们找到需要的人了
We found the man we need.
副巡官  我想进行一个秘密任务
Captain Hauptsturmführer, we are talking about a secret mission.
我需要一个经过训练的俄语翻译
I need a trained Russian translator.
一个集中营能让出来的人
Someone from the camp, whom they can afford to spare.
马上
Immediately!
我们还没正式见过  士兵
We have never formally met, soldier.
不过你还记得1941年11月27日的坦克战  对吧
But do you remember the tank fight on November 27, 1941?
邻近莫斯科的涅菲尔多小村
The Nyefjodov village near Moscow?
你消灭了那一百个俄罗斯人吗
Did you liquidate your hundred Russians?
我至少射中了你
Well, I shot you.
你看起来不错
You look good.
无可救药
Incorrigible.
不适合集中营工作的人
Not suitable for any work at the camp.
都会被清除掉
Prisoner must be liquidated.
但我会给你另一个活下来的机会
But I will give you another chance to live.
你可以组建一只俄罗斯坦克部队
You can choose and prepare a Russian tank crew.
在规定的某天  要在训练场和射击场上
On a designated day at the training & shooting range,
向我的军官学员展示你杰出的坦克战斗技巧
you will show your exceptional tank fighting skills to my cadets.
你不会有实弹  而是用哑弹来标记命中率
You won't have live ammunition but duds instead to mark the hits
你要使用你的坦克部署技能
You will use just your tanks deployment skills
来布置并分配我的部下
to subvert and out manuveur the cadets.
如果你死在场上
If you are killed on the range ...
那么你就死得像战场上的士兵
well then you died like a soldier on a battlefield.
如果你赢了  你可能会活下来
If you win then you might just survive,
你必须组建一只新的小队
you must choose a new crew.
但是我已经毁了一组队员了
But I've already ruined one
我的第一组队员
my first crew.
你尽力了
You fought fiercely.
我只在自己的土地上战斗  德国佬
I fought in my own land, Fritz.
我在等待你的答复
I am awaiting your response.
去死吧
Fuck you.
我数到五
I will count to five.
一
One.
二
Two.
三
Three.
四
Four.
住手
Halt.
听起来不错  好  我同意
It will be good fun. Ok I agree.
不用翻译了
It doesn't have to be translated.
明智的选择
Good choice commander.
说出名字和军衔
Your name and rank?
伊夫斯金  中尉
Lieutenant Ivuskin
站起来
Stand up.
把他拖走
Take him off
这28双鞋经过了测试
耐磨度合格
Acceptable for wear.
集中营已全到场
The camp is in formation.
183 82名囚犯
385名病人
32人在晚上死去
During the night, 32 people died.
好
All right.
清点完毕
The camp is accounted for.
183 82名囚犯
让这些囚犯出列
Call out these prisoners.
这12名囚犯里选出3人
The 3 priosners selected from this group of 12
这个人将会指派一个特别的
by this man will be assigned a special
某种意义上有点愉快的任务
somewhat enjoyable assignment.
他们达到了指标
They match the criteria.
维修部
Workshops
这坦克浑身上下散发着死尸的恶臭
This tank stinks of death
看着就是从34那里生产出来的
Looks like a tank from the 34th.
差不多就是这样吧
Not quite.
这辆坦克是刚刚从前线运过来的
This tank is fresh from from the war front.
看看那挺口径85的大炮
Looks like the new 85 caliber cannon.
至少85吧
No less.
伊夫斯金
Ivuskin.
你的新任务就是修复这辆坦克
Your new assignment is to restore this tank.
一周后  我们进行一次测试
After a week we will have a trial run.
这是从东方战线刚刚拿到的俄国最新款式的坦克
This is the latest Russian tank. We got it from the eastern front.
据说这种坦克可以击败我们的虎式坦克
They say it can defeat our Tiger tanks.
先把坦克上的尸体处理掉  然后清理一下炮塔
First remove the dead bodies and then clean the turret.
开工吧
Get started.
乘组人员  站成一列
Crew, stand in formation.
从现在开始  我就是你们的指挥官
From now on I am your commander.
你们要执行我所有的命令  不能对我有任何质疑
You will execute all my commands and don't dare question me.
我可以问一个问题吗  指挥官同志
If I may ask a question Commander Comrade?
说吧
Yes,
我们的作战任务是什么
What is our combat mission?
首要任务是击溃敌军
The primary task is defeating the enemy.
目前来说  我们这些狗屎  只能任由他们摆布
Temporarily, us pieces of shit... we are at their disposal.
听着  朋友  我才应该是指挥官
Listen, my friend, I could be the commander,
我可比你强很多
and much better than you.
你都还没问我们  是不是愿意加入你的坦克小队
You haven't even asked us if we want to be in your tank crew. .
米科拉  没有人想死在这
Mykola, nobody wants to die here.
伙计们
guys,
我们必须修好这辆坦克  让它再次成为战争机器
we have to repair this tank and make it a fighting machine again.
用它打败那些德国渣渣
To use against green German cadets.
我们会打败他们的
We'll beat them.
如果我们想在这场战争占据上风  我们就必须
If we want to live beyond this war, we will need to
让这家伙再次成为无可匹敌的机器
make this a super excellent machine once again
我们一定要全力以赴
we will do our job.
还有问题吗
Any more questions?
我们现在就是供德国人玩弄的角斗士吗
Are we now gladiator play things for the Germans?
书上就是这么说的
I read that happens in a book.
-如果你加入这次行动的话  -我加入
-If you agree... -then I agree.
要是没有达成一致的话  我就如实汇报了
If there is no agreement then I report it as so
然后我们就回集中营去
and we go back to camp.
我不想再被奴役了  现在我要留在这里战斗
I have had enough pulling wagons I'm will be fighting here for now.
你怎么说
And what do you say?
这只是暂时的谋生之计  但之后怎么办
It's survival for now, but what's next?
这里就是战场  同志
There's a fight, Comrade.
还是说你忘了  我们处于战争之中
Or have you forgot, that we are in war?
我没有忘记
I have not forgotten.
下命令吧
What's the command,
指挥官同志
Comrade Commander.
内部环境简直难以忍受  应该先消消毒
The interior is unbearable. It should be disinfected.
坦克内部全是死去的俄兵
The interior of the tank is full of dead Russian crew.
我请求给这些人
I ask for permission we be allowed
一个体面的葬礼
to give these men a proper burial.
我没意见
I do not mind.
把实弹弹壳放在毯子下面
Put the live shells under the blankets.
同志们  我们也很生气
We're pissed off too Comrades.
斯齐托帕
Sztyopa.
伙计们  有人来了
Guys, someone is coming in.
那应该有人发出个警报信号的
Someone should make an alert signal.
怎么了
What?
你有让我发信号吗
Did you tell me to make a noise? Zörögj.
为什么要
Because?
带点骨气吧
With bone.
伊奥诺夫  男人点  别总在最后下注
Ionov, be a man and never add below.
队员们  我弄了个沙盘战术地图
Crew. Here's a rough tactical map in the sandbox.
这个精确的训练营模型是我
It is an accurate model of the training range
一点一点拼出来的  让我们来研究一下吧
little by little it is coming toghether. Let's study it.
要弄清楚所有人  所有零件  尤其是国际部件
Get to know everyone everything especially the International components
如果我把这首诗的歌词混合起来  会怎么样
And if I mix the words of the poem?
-伊奥诺夫  -在
-Ionov. -Yes.
有空多和伏尔索克放松放松  帮助那些有需要的人
Have fun with Volcsok in your spare time help the needy.
明白  我会帮助那些有需要的人
I understand, I help the needy.
给你
To you ...
我们在这里
We were here.
这是
This is ...
坦克
tank.
-指挥官  -在
-Commander. -Yes.
来私下跟你说几句
A few words in private with you.
我去修理下前探照灯
I'm going to repair the headlamp.
你发现什么了
What did you find out?
到时候你就会知道了
You'll figure it out in time.
我们是打算用坦克从射击场逃走吗
Are we escaping from inside the shooting range using the tank?
然后
And then,
到300公里外的捷克共和国那里
on to the Czech Republic 300 kilometers from here.
我们会有一个新的T34坦克
We will have a new T-34 tank.
走主路只需要6小时
计划就是这样吗
and that's it,
如果没有失误的话
with no slip-ups.
考虑一下吧  斯蒂潘
Think about it, Stepan
我们有6发实弹
We have 6 rounds of live ammunition.
如果你愿意冒这个险  那我们就有很好的机会
And if you take the risk, there is a good chance.
红军最好的领导人永远与我们同在
In fact, it's with us the best leader of the Red Army.
你只是口上说说罢了
You can say that.
你还记得在莫斯科的时候
You remember back near Moscow,
我们能把德国装甲部队虐成灰
we crushed that German armored company into the dirt.
米科拉  我的朋友啊  那都是之前的事了
Mikola, my friend, it was way back then.
我们现在就是陷入困境的孤狼
We're fighting now like a desperate wolf.
是孤狼
to
但也渴望自由啊  斯蒂潘
waiting for freedom, Stepan.
自由就在眼前
There's freedom.
你要跟我一起干吗
Are you with me?
如果你心怀希望  那么奇迹就会发生
If you want a miracle, then it will be a miracle.
我听你的  指挥官  我加入
I'm with you, Commander, I'm with you.
把平台先造出来  斯塔普
Build the plane out of here, Stypop.
伊夫斯金  去见一下上级
Ivuskin, go see the boss.
我们的上级在克里姆林宫  小姑娘
Our boss is in the Kremlin, little girl.
进来吧
Come in.
啊  同事啊
Ah, colleague.
过来吧
Come in.
维修坦克的任务进行的怎么样了啊
How are you coming on restoring the tank?
还需要两到三天
Two or three more days.
坐下吧
Sit down.
一场战斗就要来临了  伊夫斯金  我必须提醒一下你的使命
There will soon be a fight, Ivuskin. And I must define your mission.
伊夫斯金  我可以直呼你的大名吗
Ivuskin, it's OK that I call you by that name?
人们都叫我尼古拉
People call me Nikolai
我们的名字有点关联啊  我叫克劳斯  是尼古拉斯的缩写
We are related in name. I'm Klaus. It's short for Nikolaus.
能听懂吗  尼古拉  尼古拉斯
Do you understand? Nikolai -Nikolaus.
克劳斯
Klaus.
好了
Well.
听着  尼古拉
Listen, Nikolai.
你在这里
You here...
你从这里开始
You begin here.
在训练场上
On the training field.
我的虎式坦克
My Tiger tanks
他们挡在了你们的行动路线上
they're blocking you from movement.
你有仔细看着我吗
Are you watching me carefully?
利用我们隐藏的机动性
Using our hidden maneuvers
我会操控坦克巧妙的避开撞击
I'll deftly try getting away from a hit upon our tank.
之前在莫斯科附近的小村庄的时候
Back in that little village near Moscow,
你是躲在了干草垛下面吗
were you hiding under a haystack?
是的  我们就躲在那里
Yes, we were right there.
黎明前一小时  我们采取了行动
One hour before dawn we took our position.
花了点时间  用稻草把坦克藏了起来
We had little time to cover the tank with straw.
如果被发现的话  我会用炮火轰炸的
If I had noticed I would have covered it with artillery.
但你没有发现
But you didn't notice.
干杯吧
Cheers.
祝你肝肠两断
May your liver crack in half.
祝你幸福长寿
A long and happy life to you.
加入我们吧  我们在赫尔曼 戈林所在地等你
Come with us. hermann göring location
用力点  加快速度
Pul it harder and faster.
当心
Watch out.
小队  站成一列
Squad. Stand in formation.
立正
Attention.
好的  不要浪费时间了
All right. Let's not waste time.
测试开始
Start the test run.
乘组人员  站到自己的岗位上
Crew. Man your positions.
-收到  -收到
-Roger that. -Roger that.
乘组人员  进行汇报
Crew, sound your reports.
-已就位  -已就位
-Ready. -Ready.
所有人已就位
Is everyone ready.
前进
Forward.
收到
Roger that.
看看  这才是辆真正的坦克
Here, this is a real tank.
就像是纯品白兰地
Like premium Cognac.
来吧  跳舞吧  斯蒂潘 萨维尔耶维奇
Come on, let's dance, Stepan Szaveljevics.
来支芭蕾舞吧  指挥官同志
This is a ballet, Comrade Commander.
天鹅湖  来吧
The Swan Lake. Hang on.
柴可夫斯基  天鹅湖
Tchaikovsky: Swan Lake -Suite
来点有难度的
Give him Belarusian.
这招叫旋转木马
It's a carousel.
这招是莫斯科的沃罗涅日  你们都去死吧
Moscow -Voronezh, to hell with you.
怎么了  你们吓出屎了吗
What, did you shit yourself yet?
别吓着了  这可是欢庆时刻
Get it out, Quasimodo.
蒂利克  在整个射击场周围布置下反坦克地雷
Thielicke, install anti-tank mines around the entire shooting range.
明白  长官
Yes sir.
你好啊  美人  进来吧  给你看看我们的坦克
Hello my Beauty. Come in and I'll show you our tank.
怎么了
What happened?
贾格尔已命令部下做好战斗准备
Jäger has ordered combat preparedness for the cadets.
现在整个训练营周围都有反坦克地雷
There are now anti-tank mines around the entire training range.
你确定要逃走吗
Are you sure you're going to escape?
逃出哪里
Escape where?
逃出这里
Out of here.
科尔贾  我不聋不瞎
Kolja, I'm not deaf and blind.
如果我们有地图的话
If we had a map ...
我可以去贾格尔的办公室拿到地图
I'll get the map From Jäger's office.
不行  德国人会第一个怀疑你
No, you will be the first person the Germans will suspect.
你要随身带着地图
And you will carry it with you.
不行
No.
科尔贾  我宁愿和你一起死也不想在这个监狱里活下去
Kolja, I'd rather die with you than live any longer in this prison.
这是一把钥匙的蜡模  用来做钥匙
This is a wax impression of the keys, make the keys.
我不想一个人留在这里
I can't stay here alone.
我宁可去死
I would rather die.
士兵们
Cadets.
今天  要进行战斗测试
Today the battle trials are beginning.
我相信  你们会是可以继承德国精神的人
I'm sure you will prove to be worthy heirs to the German spirit.
记住了
Remember.
如果你们学会如何正确的与俄国人交战
If you learn to properly fight the Russians,
那么当面对盎格鲁撒克逊人的时候  就会是小儿科
then when up against the Anglo-Saxons it will be child's play.
德意志帝国会统治世界
The Reich dominates the world.
祝你们好运
Good luck.
-必胜  -万岁
-Sieg. -Heil.
伙计们
Guys ...
他们包围了训练营和射击场
They have surrounded this training & shooting range.
我们需要直接从正门闯出去
We have to break straight through the main gate.
一开始  会有三只虎式坦克与我们交战
There will initally be three Tigers against us.
我们有6发实弹
We have six live rounds of ammunition,
和30公里的燃料
and 30 kilometers worth of fuel.
有些话我要说
I have to say say something.
时机已到
The time has come,
我们已经等了数年之久
we have been waiting for many years.
对敌人有着满腔怒火
Angry and hateful for the enemy
陷阵之志  有死无生
despising death,
我发誓  要在他们的地盘上消灭那些法西斯恶棍
I swear to destroy the fascist villains on their own land.
我发誓
I swear.
乘组人员
Crew,
开始战斗吧
Let's fight.
对不起了小子们  愿上帝照顾好你们
Sorry boys, may God take care of you.
四枚反坦克弹和两枚穿甲榴弹
尝尝这个  德国鬼子
Pray you Gerrys.
报告俄国人的位置
Report the position of the Russians.
俄方坦克现已启动
The Russian tank is now operational.
不错
Not bad.
部队们准备完毕
The cadets are on the line.
好的
All right.
俄国人已进入战场
The Russians on the field.
好的  继续
All right, more.
哦  天啊
Oh, boy.
简直不敢相信
This is too good to be true.
我们的坦克进入战场
Our tanks approach the field.
上校  您的烟斗
Standartenführer, here is your pipe you wanted.
一个不错的开始
Not a bad start.
你要去哪里
Where are you going?
我要引用我的11号条例
I am using my regulation No 11
经帝国专员副总指挥  图林根 弗里茨 索克尔
labor use by imperial permission of the Commissioner.
许可的劳工条例
Thuringia, Fritz Sauckel obergruppenführer.
请求单次离开集中营的许可
One-time exit permission from the camp.
晚上8点前返回这里  去吧
Return no later than 8 PM. Go.
再见了  你个白痴
Goodbye, you idiot.
开门
Open.
使用烟幕是一个很好的技巧
It's a good trick to use a smoke screen.
你预料到了吗
Did you expect this?
这位俄罗斯指挥官并不愚蠢
This Russian commander is not stupid.
愿上帝保佑
God bless you.
-启动  离开这个位置  -收到
-Lead off, leave this position. -I understand.
看看他们两个
Look at both of them.
好的  来吧  好孩子  给我们看看你的计划
Well, come on, baby boy, show us your plan.
伏尔索克  你知道出口的
Volcsok, you know the exit.
-再左一点  -收到  左一点
-Farther to the left. -I understood, to the left.
就绪
Ready.
开火
Fire.
那是什么鬼  贾格尔
What the hell was that, Jäger?
命中  命中
A hit. A hit.
他妈的太好了
Come on, fucking great.
很好  伏尔索克  乘胜追击  前进
That was nice, Volcsok. Lead on, forward.
第一辆虎式已不复存在
Volcsok the first Tiger is no more
他们为什么还不反击
Why don't they return fire?
他们打算再次进攻吗
Are they planning to attack again?
我们的火炮在哪里
Where is our artillery fire?
快点  快点
Hurry -hurry.
进入战斗状态  瞄准那座山
Catch up to the fight. Target the hill.
接通所有坦克兵
Open all the tank staff lines
所有单位注意  进入一级战备状态
Attention to all units. Go to full combat preparedness.
一级战备状态
Full combat preparedness.
已接通
Connected.
贾格尔  汇报上校的情况
Jäger briefs standarfenführer.
2号坦克  报告你的位置
Tank 2, report your position.
3号坦克  你们看到什么了吗
Tank 3, what do you see?
继续  冲啊
Get on. Come on.
所有坦克  撤退
Tanks, retreat.
2号坦克  装载十口径炮
Tank 2, 10 cannon.
3号坦克  装载十一口径炮
Tank 3, 11 cannon.
当你看到敌人时  立即开火
When you see the enemy, fire immediately.
他到底在哪里啊
Where in the hell is he?
指挥官  我需要指示
Commander, I need an instruction.
-伊奥诺夫  上膛一枚榴弹  -收到
-Ionov, load a cracker shell. -I understand.
就绪
Ready.
榴弹已上膛
It's ready.
该死
Fucking Hell.
敌方坦克在10点钟方向
Hostile tank at 10 o'clock position.
记住这一炮  你们这些狗娘养的
Remember this one you sons of whores.
你们这些畜生
You wild animals.
来吧  正前方  继续攻击
Come on, ahead, more.
-在哪  -正前方  斯塔普
-Where is it? -Straight ahead, Stypop.
斯塔普  正前方
Stypop, straight ahead.
-就藏在仓库后面  -收到
-Hide behind the warehouse. -I understand.
维塔利  来吧
Vitaly, Come on.
抓住我的手  指挥官
Grab my hand, Commander.
准备好迎战
Get ready for battle.
坚持住  伙计们
Hold on, guys.
我们要把它们干翻
We going to drum over them.
发生了什么
What was that?
德国汽车工业的终结
The end of the German car industry.
爽
Wow.
朝大门冲去  斯塔普
Head for the main gate, Stypop.
那里有架机关枪
There is machine guns.
驾驶员  关窗
Driver. Close the window.
快  摧毁他们  伏尔索克
Come on, destroy them Volcsok
收到
Roger that.
我们可以碾碎他们
We could smash ....
去大门  萨维尔耶维奇
To the gate, Szaveljevics.
撞开大门
Break on through.
万岁
Hurray
别他妈的录了
For fuck sake stop recording
下午好啊  女士们
Good afternoon Ladies.
你今天要去哪里呀  我的美人
And where do you go today my Beauty?
干得好  贾卡瓦同志
Good work Comrade Jarceva.
祝你们好运  女士们
Good luck ladies.
不害怕的话就跳进来吧
Hop inside if you are not afraid.
我们先去布拉格
First we go to Prague.
腾点地方
Move over.
你好啊
Hi
-你好  -你们好  我的朋友们
-Hello. -Hello my friends.
再见  女士们
Goodbye, ladies.
这里  就是你的座位
Here, this will be your place to sit.
欢迎来到我们的坦克
Welcome to our tank.
接通应急中心  汇报所有损失
Open the Emergency Center line. Report all losses.
向区政府报告情况
Report the situation in the district administration. Class 1 / A.
向炮兵部队  装甲分队发出警报
Alert the artillery, armor sub-unit.
收到
Yes.
封锁半径50公里内的所有道路
Closing the roads 50 kilometers radius.
我会抓住你的
I'll catch you
趁德国佬还没反应过来  继续前进
Press on Driver until the Fritzers wake up.
燃料就快用完了  指挥官
The fuel will soon run out, Commander.
我们的座驾饿了  好久没喝过东西了
Our bird is hungry, It did not drink full for a long time
离这最近的城镇有20公里远
The nearest town It is 20 kilometers away.
去那
Get there.
嘿  德国佬  给我们加满柴油  明白吗
Hey Fritz, fill us up with diesel. Do you understand?
斯蒂潘  周围的墙里有什么异常吗
Stepan, problems with any walls?
我只想把它们轰倒
I might have a habit of knocking them down.
这里没什么可疑的人  这个城镇太小了
Strange people in this hinterland, the town is so small
可能也就有几个警察
A few policemen probably.
所以让我们像参加游行一样自豪地行驶吧
Let's move proudly like we are in a parade.
指挥官同志  怎么了
Comrade Commander. Yes.
太阳已经下山了  而我们还没有吃任何东西
The Sun is already setting and we haven't eaten anything yet.
下达命令让我把这座城市夷为平地吧
Give us the command to squash the city.
掠夺不是我们的风格
Pilaging is not our style.
但你不想吃饭吗
But don't you want to eat?
我想  但我们要请求食物
I want to eat but we will ask for food.
伊奥诺夫  伏尔索克  准备出舱
Ionov, Volcsok, prepare for landing.
去找补给  你只有5分钟时间
Get what we need. You have only 5 minutes.
一个非常听话的
A local police officier ...
当地警察
and quite obedient.
-把步枪递过来  -给
-Hand over the rifle. -Here you go.
他去了帐篷那里  尼可蒂姆发现了他
He's gone to the tent, that was caught by Nicodemus .
谢谢
Thanks.
女孩们  他们吃变质的肉吗
Girls, did they eat spoiled meat?
我吃过了  但我觉得没什么特别的
I ate, but nothing special about it.
敬你幸福
Here's to your happiness.
非常感谢  再见
... and thank you very much. Goodbye.
斯塔普  我们走的越远越好
Stypop, The farther away we can get the better,
今晚就躲起来
we will hide tonight.
右急转
Turn hard right
大家都还好吗
Is everybody alive.
-贾卡瓦  -我还活着
-Jarceva. -I'm alive.
那是什么
What is this?
88步兵连  防空炮
这条路似乎已经被堵死了
The roads seem to be blocked.
斯塔普  你还记得兔子的老把戏吗
Stypop, do you remember the rabbit'S old hiding trick?
我记得
I remember
呼叫总部
Staff
明白
Yes
伊万奇迹般地从所有防空武器攻击范围内消失了
Ivan had miraculously disappeared from all air defense weapons.
伊就真是个天才
Ivan is ingeniousl.
正如我所担心的
As I feared he would
他们在捷克摩拉维亚保护国  要去边境
in the Czech-Moravian Protectorate they're going to the border.
我们把他们从主干道驱离
We diverted them from the main road
所以现在我们可以把范围缩小到小路上
now we narrow them down into the smaller back roads.
下一步计划是什么
What is our next step?
他们会被困住
They will be trapped.
蒂利克  请求空中支援
Thielicke, ask for air support.
收到
Yes.
还是一个疯子
and a psycho also.
我将允许与阿纳内贝通话
I will allow the connection to Ahnenerbe.
我现在要去柏林了
I'm going to Berlin now.
贾格尔  如果到早上那辆坦克还没被解决的话
Jäger, if this is not solved by the morning
那我就不能再袒护你了
then I can't defend you anymore.
我们快到了  矿山那边就是捷克斯洛伐克
We are almost there, the Krušné hory. Czechoslovakia.
再飞远点  我知道他们就在下面
One more flyover. I know they are down here.
上校  我们的燃料要用完了
Colonel Standartenführer, we're running out of fuel.
不  飞的再远点
No, let's go further.
上校  我们必须现在返回基地
Colonel Standartenführer, right now we must fly back to the base.
再飞远点
Let's go further.
我再重复一遍  我们必须马上回去
I'll repeat it, right away we have to go back.
他们就在附近了  冷静点
They are near. Stay calm.
-降低高度  -是
-Go lower. -Yes.
指挥官  油箱状态良好  但我们的水箱快沸了
Commander, the tank is good, but our engine water is near boiling
停下来休息一下  我们要完好无损地到达目的地
Stop and rest, we have to get through intact.
我们在这附近过夜
We'll stay overnight near here.
收到
Roger that.
无意冒犯  我以为我们要去柏林
Just a word, I thought we were going to Berlin.
但柏林在反方向
Berlin is the opposite way.
沿着路的左边尽可能地低飞
Fly as low as possible left on the road.
保持低海拔
At low elevation.
再低点
Even lower.
Lower..
逮到你了
Gotcha.
斯蒂潘 莱瓦內维奇
Stepan Levanevich
怎么了
Yeah?
你知道现在该怎么办吗
You know what to do now?
我们晚上在树林里走不远
We can't make it further in the woods at night.
我们现在要等到天亮
We will sit tight for now and wait for dawn.
伊奥诺夫  准备驻扎  伏尔索克  检查一下周围
Ionov. Tűzifáért, Volcsok, explore this area.
乐意效劳
I am happy.
-贾卡瓦  -怎么了
-Jarceva. -Yes.
做点饭
Cook some food?
没问题
Of course.
指挥官同志  我想自由活动一会儿
Comrade Commander, I want to ask for some free time.
-怎么了  -我们面前就有一个天然游泳池
-Tell me. -We have a natural swimming pool in front of us.
我建议我们都洗个澡
I suggest we all take a bath.
别太吵就行了
Just don't make a lot of noise.
太好了
Hurray
我们自由了
We are Free
我们已就位
We're in position .
总部来电话了
HQ has called.
找到他们了
I have found them.
已精确定位到俄国人的位置
The Russians are near Klingenthal-Zwickau-Chemnitz-Annaberg
在我们的射程之内
they are within our range.
通知第一师
Alert the the first division.
明白
Yes.
接通柏林
Connect to Berlin.
柏林  快
Berlin, fast.
这里是贾格尔上校
This is Jäger standarfenführer.
我发现他们了  我们会在早上歼灭他们
I found them. In the morning we will annihilate them.
子弹在
The bullet is flying
山丘上飞
above the mountains.
笔直射入他雪白的胸膛
Straight into his white chest
笔直的
straight,
射入他雪白的胸膛
into his white chest.
血溅成一条小河
Blood spills down in a rivulet.
哦  血溅出
Oh, the blood spilled,
像一条小河
now like a small river.
流入多瑙河
flows into the Danube.
那是他母亲汲水的地方
where his mother draws water
也是他母亲思念儿子的地方
and where she remembers her son.
母亲  母亲  远离战争的
Woe, mother, mother, far from war
你的儿子
your son
回家了
has come home...
你们是真的
and it's the truth you guys.
够了
Enough.
在斯拉夫科夫斯基之前  有一片50公里长的森林
Before Slavkovsky there is a 50 kilometer long forest.
我想我们已经完成我们的任务了
I think we've done our job.
到目前为止  我们的计划一直领先德国佬
We have out smarted the Fritzers so far.
长官  我们现在应该把坦克沉到这个湖里
Commander, we should now sink the tank in this lake,
休息  然后分头行动
rest up and then split up into separate groups.
我们救了自己
We have saved ourselves.
米克拉  我不是因为你的命令才跟随你的
Mikola, it's not because of your orders that I'm with you,
我是自愿的
I came voluntarily.
-我能说点什么吗  -当然
-Can I say something? -yes, go ahead..
我会为坦克感到遗憾的
I'll be sorry for the tank.
长官  我不会离开你的身边
Commander, without you I'm not going anywhere.
我们是红军士兵
We're Red Army soldiers.
我们发过誓
We made an oath,
誓死摧毁敌人
to the last drop to our blood to destroy the enemy.
但是放弃一匹良驹实在可惜
But abandoning a perfectly good horse is a shame.
伏尔索克
Volcsok.
你的实力和听力都像鹰一样敏锐
Not only your vision, but your hearing is like an eagle.
你应该去马戏团
You should be in the circus.
如果没有我你会迷失在河上的  驾驶员
Without me you'd wander lost enflessly on the river tank driver.
所以现在休息一下
So give it a rest now.
好吧
All right.
我们最后50公里继续使用坦克
We will use the tank for the last 50 kilometers.
大家轮流守夜  我们4点离开
Let's rotate sleep shifts. We leave at 4 o'clock.
每个小时换一次岗
Change the lookout every hour.
看看这个夜晚
Look at this night.
科尔贾
Kolja,
你有什么渴望吗
do you want something?
当然有
of course I do.
那就是永远爱你
To love you forever.
天啊  科勒尼卡
Hell, Kolenyka.
我等你一辈子了
I've been waiting for you all my life.
亲爱的  醒醒
My Darling, wake up.
醒醒  你必须起来了
Wake up, you have to.
队员们  起来了  贾格尔开始行动了
Crew, get up. It's Jäger on the move.
天亮的时候道路会被封锁起来
The road will be blocked by sunrise.
我们趁还黑着突围出去
While still dark we break through.
安佳
Anja.
你不能和我们一起上坦克
You can't come with us in the tank.
我不会独自留在这的  我不会离开你
I won't stay here without you. I'm not going anywhere without you.
安佳  听我说
Anja, listen to me.
只要计划得当我们都能离开这里
With a wise plan we can all get out of here.
带着你的东西  朝正东方走
Take your bearing now, and you go due east.
看
Look.
我们在这里
We are here on the map.
这条小路经过克林根塔尔镇
This path goes by the town of Klingenthal.
你要去村子的左边
You have to stay to the left of the village.
那里有一大片开阔地
You will reach a great clearing here.
在那里等我们
Wait for us there.
要是明天晚上我们还没出现
If we don't meet you tomorrow night...
你就继续上路
then continue on further without us.
不要在白天赶路
Travel only at night.
记住一直向正东走  明白了吗
But always walk due east. Do you understand?
我明白
I understand.
安内克斯卡
Anyecska.
很好  亲爱的
That's right, my dear.
你不用害怕  同志
You don't have to be afraid, Comrade.
森林会保护你
The forest will protect you.
谢谢
Thanks.
拿着  你或许需要它
Keep this sister, you may need it.
-直到我们再次相遇  -直到我们再次相遇
-Till we meet again. -Till We meet.
再会  亲爱的
Goodbye, dear.
就这样  现在快走吧
That's it, go. Leave now.
有陷阱是吗
I smell a trap?
前面情况有古怪
There's an odd suitcase ahead in a stroller.
不是德国人
It's not German.
这座城市似乎已经被疏散
The city seems to have been evacuated.
他们在暗中等待我们
They're hiding waiting for us.
斯蒂潘  撤退吧
Stepan, let's back track,
离开大路  我们走小路吧
Get off the main road. Let's take an alley way.
准备交战
Prepare to engage.
虎式坦克在左边
Tiger on the left.
又来一个
And a second one.
这些混蛋
Those bastards
小炮弹可穿不透他们的装甲
Cracker shell will not punch through their armor
我们攻击他们的软肋
We'll instead bounce it into their belly
-知道了吗  -明白
-Got it? -I understand.
延长点火时间
Delay the fuse
-你一定要射准  -我知道  长官  我知道
-You must have a clear shot. -I know, Commander. I know.
斯塔普  别弄出什么动静
Stypop, don't stick out.
-瞄准了  -开火
-Tiger in the sights -Fire
-这个蠢货上天堂了  -干的漂亮  伏尔索克
-This pig is off to Heaven. -That was great work, Volcsok.
没想到这一招这么管用
I am surprised this trick worked so well.
现在短暂休息  调整一下
Now, a short breather to rest.
114坦克被毁
The 114 tank was destroyed
俄罗斯人朝空地前进中
The Russians are moving towards open space
返回储备区
Fall back to the reserve position
小心行动
Move carefully
停
Halt
我出去看看
I will look around
街宽8米
The width of the street is 8 meters.
移速20千米每小时的坦克每秒移动5.5米
A Tank moving 20 km/h is 5.5 meters per second. ....
我们需要一个诱饵
there is a need to distract.
德国佬每1.5秒能射击一次
The fritz can fire every 1.5 seconds.
一旦坦克出现不要失手
When the tank appears don't miss it.
明白
Yes.
-长官下一步做什么  -坐好  斯塔普
-What's next Commander? -Sit tight, Stypop
我们被三台虎式坦克包围了
We are pinned down by three Tigers.
我们的计划是
Our plan is....
但是首先  谁愿意为大家承担最大风险
but first, who will undertake for us the biggest risk of all?
还有谁这么勇敢  除我之外
Who else is brave enough but me,
下令吧  长官
just give the order my Commander.
看  我们在这
Look. We are here.
天色还很暗  现在是我们的机会
It's still dark for cover. Now is our chance.
你的目标是这架坦克  记下来  明白了吗
This German Tiger is your target. Take note. Do you understand?
我很明白  很明白
I understand perfectly, perfectly.
现在就去吧
Go now.
吉曼
Gyemjan
祝你好运
Good luck
必须的  撒拉弗
Of course, Seraphim.
-当你听到爆炸声时全速前进  -朝哪前进
-When you hear the explosion then give it full throttle. -Where to?
-看见这面墙了吗  -嗯
-You see that wall? -Yes?
这后面一定有出口
There must be an exit behind it.
要是没有呢
And if there is no exit?
那我们都会死
Then we're all dead.
小心手榴弹
Grenade
出发了  伏尔索克
Come on, Volcsok.
该死  我们没命中坦克
Dam. We didn't hit the tank dead on.
115和112去主街区  让我们把他们揪出来
这有出口
Here's an exit
虎式坦克在我们前方
Tiger right in front of us
旋转炮塔180度
Spin turret 180 degrees now
敌军也在转动炮塔
Enemy is turning his turret also
装弹
Load shell
好  明白
Yes yes
混蛋
You bitch
炮台在什么位置
Come on Where's the turret?
清理炮弹
Clear the breach
妈的
Shit
装弹
Load
去你妈的
God dam
准备开火
Fire on load
我们还活着
We're alive
坦克  停下
Tank, stop.
准备开火
Prepare to fire
下辈子再会  兄弟们
Goodbye my brothers.
开火
Fire.
刚才是谁开着那辆坦克
Who just started their tank engine?
是英勇的伏尔索克  他还活着
It's our brave Volcsok, he's still alive
他怎么得到的虎式坦克
How did he get a Tiger for himself?
我们中队现在有两辆坦克了
We have TWO tanks in our squadron now
炮兵  瞄准新目标  虎式坦克112里有叛军
Gunner, set new target. Rebel in Tiger Tank 112
准备连续射击
Prepare for rapid fire.
我下不去手  那个坦克里有我的德国战友
I can't fire. In that tank are my fellow German mates.
你的德国伙伴已经被俄国人杀死了
Your German mates are dead killed by the Russians
敌人正在112坦克里向我们开火
In the 112 tank the enemy is now firing on us.
他想杀了我们
He wants to destroy us.
离开这里  快  快
Get out of there. Quick, quick.
装弹
Load
我们又一次要和魔鬼战斗了
Once again we fight the Devil.
吉曼
Gyemjan.
你这个混蛋
You fucker
不需要葬礼  他会是幸存的
No need for a funeral, he will be the lucky one.
所以我们现在处于对峙状态吗
So now we're in a stand-off?
好  让我们看看下一个挑战是什么
OK, let's see the next challenge
狗和切碎的肝包
The dog and the chopped liver package.
给你五分钟  尼古拉斯
In Five minutes, Nikolaus.
现在我们扯平了  同志
Now we're even comrades
我就在这里  尼古拉
I'm right here, Nikolai
队员们  听着我们的计划
Crew... this is our plan.
斯塔普  在桥上全速前进
Stypop, on the bridge it is full speed ahead.
然后听我指挥进行最后的行动
Then listen for my command to the final maneuvers
撒拉弗  准备大炮
Seraphim, prepare the cannon
最后一炮  已就绪
Last shell. Ready.
我们必须尽可能靠近
We have to get as close as possible
我们的机会是千分之一
Our chance is one in a thousand.
我们的作战计划很完美
Our battle plan is eleganance and glitter.
会让他们好好看看我们的表演的
Finally we will play in the circus.
准备好了吗
Ready for action?
听起来计划不错
Sounds like a good plan
英勇的伏尔索克同志  不要死
Brave comrade Volcsok, don't die on us
前进
Forward
我们在天上的神父
Our Father who art is in heaven,
愿人都尊你的名为圣
hallowed be your name
我现在还不想杀你
I'm not gonna kill you just yet.
我会先把你的头取下来  停
I'll take your fucking head off first. Stop
右转
Hard to the Right
愿你的国降临  愿你的旨意行在人间仍被遵从  如同在天上一样
Your kingdom come, your will be done, on earth as it is in heaven
我要打破你的护盾
I will break your shield.
左转
Hard to the Left
停
Stop.
右转
Right
宽恕我们的罪过  如同我们宽恕别人的罪
... and forgive our sins as we do forgive the sins of others
不叫我们历经冒险  救我们脱离凶恶
And lead us not into temptation but deliver us from evil
把他们的履带打掉
knock the track off side also...
撞击
Crash
开枪吧
Shoot
终于结束了吗
Is it finally over for the Fritz?
这已经足够了
That was was more than enough for now.
我们还要用坦克吗
What are we doing with the tank?
还剩有一半的燃料
It is half-full of fuel.
敌人还没有放弃
The enemy doesn't give up.
我们会带上伤员伏尔索克  然后步行前进
We will carry injured Volcsok with us and continue on foot.